I think most people think that
DJs are sort of mystical or magical.
That they have access to special people, that
they're gifted with skills behind the decks and
have access to this music that nobody else has access to.
I don't think that's true.
I think that great DJs actually
just have a message in their heart.
And when they hear certain music that resonates with
that message, they just feel compelled to share and
they have to get that message out to their audience.
Hi, I'm Avand.
By day, I'm a software engineer.
By night, I'm a DJ.
I've been doing DJing for over 13 years.
I've helped produce events, house
parties, festivals, renegades, you name it.
And music's been a huge part of my life.
So I first started DJing when my
friend handed me down his two-channel mixer.
I took to the tech really naturally,
especially having a background in software.
But what really got me excited to DJ more and
to take it more seriously were the
transformational experiences I had on the dance floor.
Those types of moments where you realize we're all
connected and we're all part of something bigger than ourselves.
I think that's what got me really
excited to take it more seriously.
When people teach themselves how to DJ, they usually
end up with gaps in their knowledge or develop bad habits.
And it's really important, especially early on, to make
sure that everything that they're learning is correct.
That way, with each repetition,
they're reinforcing the correct behavior.
It's very easy to get started as a DJ these days, but the
tricky thing about your blind spots is that you can't see them.
And I promise you that across the spectrum of the
stack, there are two to three X improvements to be
made in sound and signal flow and library and
workflow that most people just don't even think it's possible.
Headroom is the zone between normal levels and max levels.
Basically, it's about creative space so that
where you're operating normally has room in case
you need to push things or something wants to spike.
So it's all about giving yourself some breathing room.
When you stop thinking, you're able to be embodied.
And that's where the dance floor lives.
Your dancers are dancing, they're in their bodies.
They're not thinking too much.
The moment your brain turns on, you go out
of your body and you're no longer able to be
in the room, feel the vibe and set the tone.
When you deeply understand your
craft, you will spend less time thinking.
And when you're not thinking, you're able
to drop into your flow and be more creative.
Headroom is not for beginners.
It's for DJs that have already been doing it for a
while, but maybe recognize that there are some gaps
in their knowledge or some things that they could learn.
Headroom is for DJs that want to get the most out of
their equipment, the most out of their time and also want
to bring the best possible experience to their dance floors.
My hope for Headroom students is that they gain
confidence, that the curriculum really fills gaps in
their knowledge so that when they step into new
situations, they're able to perform competently and
confidently and bring the best experiences to the dance floor.
The first cohort of Headroom launches in
October and because I want to keep the chorus
small and focused, I'm only opening up 12 spots.
And I hope to see you there.